Guide to the Cornell University Office of Equal Opportunity records, 1971-1982.
Cornell University Office of Equal Opportunity records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University Office of Equal Opportunity records, 1971-1982.
10-5-1464
Cornell University Office of Equal Opportunity.
7.1 cubic ft.
Minutes, reports, and records.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Advisory Board minutes and reports and other records of the office.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The Office of Equal Opportunity handled diversity, disability, sexual harassment and other inclusion issues. The director reported to the Vice President of Human Resources. The functions of this office were changed to the Office of Workforce Diversity and Inclusion (now the Department of Inclusion and Workforce Diversity) and Student Disability Services in 1999.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Advisory Board minutes and reports and other records of the office.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University Office of Equal Opportunity.; Cornell University -- Employees.; Cornell University
Subjects:
Affirmative action programs.; Employees
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Restricted to permission of office of origin.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Affirmative Action Related Materials
Boxes 1-4, 7
Plans
Proposals
Academic Appointments
Other Materials
Series II. Campus Building Construction
Boxes 4, 6-7
Series III. Reports & Surveys
Boxes 1, 4, 7
Series IV. Publications
Box 2
Series V. Administrative Materials
Boxes 1-2, 4, 7
Series VI. Sexual Harassment Related Materials
Boxes 4, 7-8
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Affirmative Action Related Materials
  - Plans
    - Affirmative Action Plan, 1977-07-01 (Box 1, Folder 11-13)
    - Affirmative Action Plan 1977 original, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Affirmative Action Plan, 1979-07 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Affirmative Action Plan, 1979-09 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Affirmative Action Plan, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Affirmative Action Plan, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Affirmative Action Plan, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Affirmative Action Plan - Summary, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Affirmative Action Plan, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Affirmative Action Plan, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Affirmative Action Plan, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Contractor's Affirmative Action Plan, 1984-11-07 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Affirmative Action Plan, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Affirmative Action Plan, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Affirmative Action Plan Items, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Contractor's Affirmative Action Plan, 1986-01-1989-12 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Contractor's Affirmative Action Plan, 1986-07-1987-03 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Affirmative Action Plan, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Contractor's Affirmative Action Plan, 1987-01-01-1987-12-31 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Contractor's Affirmative Action Plan, 1987-08-13-1988-04-19 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Contractor's Affirmative Action Plan, 1988-03-27-1988-12-21 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Contractor's Affirmative Action Plan, 1988-07-01 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Contractor's Affirmative Action Contracts and Plans, 1988-10-11-1989-02-28 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Affirmative Action Workforce Report, 1989-01-12-1990-04-17 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Contractor's Affirmative Action Plans and Contracts, 1989-03-31-1989-10-25 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Contractor's Affirmative Action Plans and Reports, 1989-10-30-1990-08-17 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Affirmative Action Plan - Contractors, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Affirmative Action Plan - Contractors, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Affirmative Action Plan - Contractors, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Proposals
    - AA Search Plan Proposal - Agriculture & Life Sciences, 1981-07-1982-06 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - AA Search Plan Proposal - Arts & Sciences, 1981-07-1982-06 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - AA Search Plan Proposal - Biological Sciences, 1981-07-1982-06 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - AA Search Plan Proposal - Business & Public Administration, 1981-07-1982-06 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - AA Search Plan Proposal - Cooperative Extension, 1981-07-1982-06 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - AA Search Plan Proposal - Engineering, 1981-07-1982-06 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - AA Search Plan Proposal - Agriculture & Life Sciences, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - AA Search Plan Proposal - Architecture, Art, & Planning, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - AA Search Plan Proposal - Agriculture & Life Sciences, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Academic Appointments
    - Academic Women and Discrimination, Undated (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Affirmative Action - Goals and Timetables for Academic Positions, 1976-12 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - AA Statement - Academic Appointments - Arts & Sciences (Physical Sciences), 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - AA Statement - Academic Appointments - Arts & Sciences (Physical Sciences), 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - AA Statement - Academic Appointments - Arts & Sciences (Physical Sciences), 1986 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - AA Statement - Academic Appointments - Arts & Sciences (Physical and Social Sciences), 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - AA Statement - Academic Appointments - Biological Sciences & Cooperative Extension, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - AA Statement - Academic Appointments - Engineering, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - AA Statement - Academic Appointments - NYSSILR & Law School, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - AA Statement - Academic Appointments - Nutritional Sciences, Univ Library & Provost, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - AA Statement - Academic Appointments - Veterinary Medicine, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 21-22)
    - AA Statement - Academic Appointments - Arts & Sciences (Humanities), 1987 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - AA Statement - Academic Appointments - Arts & Sciences (Physical Sciences), 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - AA Statement - Academic Appointments - JGSM & Human Ecology, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Other Materials
    - Affirmative Action Office "Utilization Analysis", Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Implementing and Affirmative Action Program, Undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Affirmative Action Program, Undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Affirmative Action Advisory Board, Undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Affirmative Action Database Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Affirmative Action Conferences, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Affirmative Action Conferences, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Affirmative Action Database Correspondence, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Affirmative Action Advisory Board Meeting Minutes, 1976-1981 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Affirmative Action Alliance, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 32)
      Includes luncheon, minutes, Attitude Change Subcommittee
    - AA Advisory Board Review & Recommendations & Reporting Systems, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      Includes functions of the AA Advisory Board/Membership List
    - Information on the results of the Academic Affirmative Action Program Cornell University, 1979-01-19 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Presented to the Board of Trustees
    - Affirmative Action Committee, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 15-16)
    - Affirmative Action Update, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Affirmative Action and Utilization Reports, 1989-01-01-1989-01-31 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Series II. Campus Building Construction
  - Construction - Vet College Research Tower, Mary Donlon Asbestos Removal, Founders Hall, Goldwin Smith Hall Phase 5, Helen Newman Athletic Fields, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Construction - Upper North Campus Buildings #1, 8, and 10, Equine Park Water Improvements, Goldwin Smith Hall (Phase 6), Phillips Hall Masonry Repair Project, Lyon Hall Renovation, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Construction - Bradfield Emerson Hall, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Construction - Robert Purcell Union, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Construction - Herb Palleson, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Construction - Wilson Laboratory, Townhouses, Olin Library, Parking Garage/Athletic Field, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Construction - Upson Hall, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Biotechnology Building, 1986-08-1988-01 (Box 6, Folder 1-6)
  - Cogneration Project, 1986-08-1987-05 (Box 6, Folder 28-30)
  - Comstock Building, 1986-09-1987-05 (Box 6, Folder 31-33)
  - Statler Hotel, 1986-09-1989-04 (Box 6, Folder 60-62)
  - Clark Hall Renovations, 1986-12-1987-06 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Plant Molecular Biology, 1986-12 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Savage Hall, 1986-12-1987-10 (Box 6, Folder 54-55)
  - Space Sciences, 1986-12-1987-08 (Box 6, Folder 58-59)
  - Baker Institute, 1987-01-1988-01 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Quarterly Reports, 1987-03-1989-12 (Box 6, Folder 13-15)
  - Central Avenue Bridge, 1987-04-1987-07 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Animal Room Renovations, 1987-06-1988-02 (Box 6, Folder 17-18)
  - Humphreys Service Building, 1987-06 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Law School Addition, 1987-06-1989-04 (Box 6, Folder 40-44)
  - Fabric Filter Installation, 1987-07-1987-12 (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
  - Clara Dickson Hall Project, 1987-07-1987-09 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Graduate Student Housing, 1987-07-1989-03 (Box 6, Folder 36-38)
  - Chemical Disposal Site Security Fence, 1987-09 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Balch Hall, 1987-09 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Savage Hall Addition, 1987-10-1988-07 (Box 6, Folder 52-53)
  - 115 KV Substation, 1987-12-1990-01 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Plantation Service Buildings, 1987-12-1988-06 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Rockefeller Hall Lecture Room, 1987-12-1988-06 (Box 6, Folder 48-50)
  - Hasbrock Apartments Roof Replacement, 1987-12-1989-07 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Biotechnology Building, 1988-01-1989-05 (Box 6, Folder 21-24)
  - Life Safety, 1988-04-1989-10 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Bookstore Building, 1988-06-1989-06 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Scheolkopf Turf Replacement, 1988-06-1988-10 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Pre-Construction Meeting Memo, 1988-07-05 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Cornell Laundry, 1988-12-1989-02 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Sheldon Court, 1988-12 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Chilled Water Plant, 1989-04-1989-09 (Box 6, Folder 26-27)
  - Cornell Center Project, 1990-02 (Box 6, Folder 35)
- Series III. Reports & Surveys
  - Source Book of Academic Information on Minorities and Women at Cornell, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Minority Survey Releases, Undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Hayes Study - Annual Reports of Exempt Employees, Counts of Exempt Employees, Salary Grades, Hayes Classification Titles, Undated (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - American Indians, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Cornell in the Seventies: Goals, Priorities and Plans - background information and studies, 1973-05 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - A Commitment to the Equality: One Century Later Report of the Ad Hoc Trustee Committee on the Status of Women, 1974-01 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - A Commitment to the Equality: One Century Later Report of the Ad Hoc Trustee Committee on the Status of Women, 1974-03 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Comparable Institutional Data Survey: Some Observations (Management Systems and Analysis), 1975 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Report of the Trustee Ad Hoc Committee on the Status of Minorities, 1975-10 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Appendices for the Report of the Health Planning Steering Committee, 1976-03-01 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Report of the Task Force on Implementation - study on AA at Cornell University, 1978-05-01 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Academic Work Force Analysis, Utilization Analysis and Goals for 1979-80 through 1981-82, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Minority Survey Dev., 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Survey of Minority Faculty and Staff (#2), 1983 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Survey of Minority Faculty and Staff (#3), 1983 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Minority Faculty and Staff Survey, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Minority Survey Analysis, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Minority Survey Reports, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Minority Survey Recommendations, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Status of Women and Minorities Report, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Survey - Ancillary Services issue, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Dormitory Authority, Minority and Female Count, 1986-07-11-1987-04-10 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Minority and Female Count, 1986-07-11-1987-11-06 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Minority and Female Count, 1986-09-04-1987-04-05 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Minority and Female Count, 1986-10-03-1988-01-22 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Dormitory Authority, Minority and Female Count, 1987-04-17-1989-01-07 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Minority and Women's Utilization Report, 1987-06 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Minority and Female Count, 1987-11-13-1989-01-06 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Contractor's Affirmative Action Workforce Report, 1987-12-11-1989-07-10 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Minority and Female Count, 1988-01-10-1988-12-30 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Contractor's Minority/Women's Utilization Report, 1988-06-07-1989-06-19 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Minority and Female Count, 1988-07-10-1988-09-25 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Dormitory Authority, Minority and Female Count, 1988-10-21-1989-09-02 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Minority/Women's Business Utilization Report, 1988-12-01-1989-02-23 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Minority and Female Count, 1989-01-06-1989-03-30 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Minority/Women's Utilization Report, 1989-01-31 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Dormitory Authority, Minority and Female Count, 1989-09-08-1990-03-31 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Minority and Female Count - Central Library, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Minority and Female Count - Theory Center, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Minority and Female Count - chilled water rehab., thermal water tank, Hasbrouck Apts., 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Minority and Female Count - Noyes Lodge, Big Red Barn, S.E. Asia Program, North Campus, S.T. Olin, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Series IV. Publications
  - Dialogue Index (A Newsletter on Women's Work Issues at Cornell), 1974-1981 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Dialogue, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Dialogue, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Dialogue, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Dialogue, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Dialogue, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Dialogue, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Dialogue, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Series V. Administrative Materials
  - Conferences, Undated (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - EEO Studies Progam, Undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Memo re: letters of rationale (for waivers) to AUR from Don Johnson, Undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Job Descriptions, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Job Descriptions, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Job Descriptions, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Cornell Women's Caucus - Minutes, Memos, Notes, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Cornell Women's Caucus - Minutes, Memos, Notes, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Cornell Women's Caucus - Minutes, Memos, Notes, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Cornell Women's Caucus - Minutes, Memos, Notes, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Cornell Women's Caucus - Minutes, Memos, Notes, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Sexual Preference Correspondence - 1979, 1983, 1984, 1979-1984 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Cornell Women's Caucus - Minutes, Memos, Notes, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Press Coverage, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Interviews with current minority employees, Suggestions for Action Plans, 1983-05 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Cornell Women's Caucus - Minutes, Memos, Notes, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - OEO staff meeting minutes, 1984-06-1985-06 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - OEO Minutes, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Cornell Women's Caucus - Minutes, Memos, Notes, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Accessibility Problems on Campus, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Memo re: practice interviewing program, 1985-01-24 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Human Relations Task Force, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Cornell Women's Caucus - Letters, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - OEO staff meeting minutes, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Cornell Women's Caucus - Minutes, Memos, Notes, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - OEO staff meeting minutes, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Series VI. Sexual Harassment Related Materials
  - Sexual Harassment Policy Development, Undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Sexual Harassment - Cornell, Undated (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Sexual Discrimination, 1976-07-07 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Sexual Discrimination, 1978-05-19 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Sexual Discrimination, 1979-01-25 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Sexual Discrimination, 1980-10-09 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Sexual Discrimination, 1980-10-09 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Sexual Harassment, 1981-03-18 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Sexual Harassment, 1981-05-04 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Sexual Harassment, 1983-02-28 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Sexual Harassment, 1983-10-20 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Sexual Harassment, 1984-07-16 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Sexual Harassment, 1985-01-28 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Sexual Harassment, 1985-09-03 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Sexual Harassment, 1986-12-13 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Sexual Harassment, 1987-09-30 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Sexual Harassment - Savage Hall Construction Workers, 1987-12-08 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Sexual Harassment - Savage Hall Construction Workers, 1987-12-08 (Box 8, Folder 13a)